Guide to the Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees: 1915-1985
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees: 1915-1985
5488 B
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees.
669 linear feet.
Correspondence, Rule books, Agreements, etc.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
SUBJECTS
Names:
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees.
Subjects:
Railroads--Employees--Labor unions--United States--Sources.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Restricted. Please contact the Kheel Center Reference Archivist for access information.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
This forms a portion of collection #5488 B. The guide to the entire collection is available here.
Series CVI is arranged in 9 sub-series by Union file number.
Series CVII is arranged in 10 sub-series by Union file number.
Series CVIII is arranged in 1 sub-series by Union file number.
Series CIX is arranged in 1 sub-series by Union file number.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series CVI. 1955 GRAND LODGE CONVENTION
  - Sub-Series 518-0. 1955 Grand Lodge Convention. General
    - St. Petersburg, Florida, 1951-1953 (Box 622b, Folder 1)
    - General, 1951-1954 (Box 622b, Folder 2)
    - General, 1955 (Box 623a, Folder 1)
      1955 April
    - General, 1955-1957 (Box 623a, Folder 2)
      May 1955-57.
    - Correspondence with Representatives and Organizers, 1955 (Box 623a, Folder 3)
      January-May 1955.
    - General, 1953-1955 (Box 623a, Folder 4)
      1953-March 1955.
    - General, 1955 (Box 623a, Folder 5)
    - Cleveland, Ohio Section., 1952-1953 (Box 623a, Folder 6)
  - Sub-Series 518-1. 1955 Grand Lodge Convention. Law Committee Report
    - General, 1955 (Box 623b, Folder 1-2)
    - Amendments to the Grand Lodge Constitution, Statutes for the Government of Lodges and Protective Laws of the Brotherhood, 1954-1957 (Box 623b, Folder 3)
  - Sub-Series 518-4. 1955 Grand Lodge Convention. Appointments
    - General, 1955 (Box 624a, Folder 1)
    - Delegates; Non-Delegates, 1954-1955 (Box 624a, Folder 2)
    - Convention Committee; Constitution and Laws Committee; Petitions and Resolutions Committee; Credentials Committee; Appeals Committee; Finances, Salaries, Mileage and Per Diem Committee; Retirement and Unemployment Insurance Committee; Official Publication, 1954-1955 (Box 624a, Folder 3)
    - Committee of Tellers; State, Provincial, and Federal Legislation Committee; Sergeant-at-Arms; Guards; Special Committee; Grand Chaplain, Money Guards, 1954-1955 (Box 624a, Folder 4)
  - Sub-Series 518-5. 1955 Grand Lodge Convention. Amendments
    - 1954 Amendments to Railroad Retirement, Unemployment Insurance and Railroad Retirement Tax Acts, 1955 (Box 624a, Folder 5)
  - Sub-Series 518-6. 1955 Grand Lodge Convention. Mileage and Per Diem
    - General, 1955 (Box 624a, Folder 6)
  - Sub-Series 518-7. 1955 Grand Lodge Convention. Speakers
    - General, 1955 (Box 624a, Folder 7)
  - Sub-Series 518-8. 1955 Grand Lodge Convention. Grand President's Report
    - Universities, 1955-1957 (Box 624a, Folder 8)
    - General, 1955-1957 (Box 624a, Folder 9)
    - General, 1955 (Box 624a, Folder 10-13)
  - Sub-Series 518-9. 1955 Grand Lodge Convention. Appeals
    - General, 1955 (Box 624a, Folder 14)
  - Sub-Series 518-10. 1955 Grand Lodge Convention. Committee on Rules
    - Order of Business and Ritual, 1955 (Box 624a, Folder 15)
- Series CVII. 1959 GRAND LODGE CONVENTION
  - Sub-Series 523-0. 1959 Grand Lodge Convention. General
    - Amendments to the Grand Lodge Constitution, Statues for the Government of Lodges and Protective Laws of the Brotherhood Submitted by Grand President, 1959 (Box 624b, Folder 1)
      1959 April 10
    - Report of Committee on Grand Lodge Constitution and Laws, 1959 (Box 624b, Folder 2)
      1959 May
    - 1955-April 1959 (Box 624b, Folder 3)
    - Election Notices, 1959 (Box 624b, Folder 4)
      1959 January 9
    - Souvenir Program, 1959 (Box 624b, Folder 5)
      May 11-16, 1959.
    - General, 1959-1961 (Box 624b, Folder 6)
      May 1959-March 1961.
  - Sub-Series 523-1. 1959 Grand Lodge Convention. Resolutions
    - General, 1959 (Box 624b, Folder 7)
    - General, 1958-1959 (Box 624b, Folder 8)
    - General, 1959 (Box 624b, Folder 9-11)
    - Nos. 1-25, 1959 (Box 624b, Folder 12)
    - Nos. 26-50, 1959 (Box 624b, Folder 13)
    - Nos. 51-75, 1959 (Box 624b, Folder 14)
    - Nos. 76-100, 1959 (Box 624b, Folder 15)
    - Nos. 101-125, 1959 (Box 624b, Folder 16)
    - Nos. 126-150, 1959 (Box 624b, Folder 17)
    - Nos. 151-175, 1959 (Box 624b, Folder 18)
    - Nos. 176-200, 1959 (Box 624b, Folder 19)
    - Nos. 201-225, 1959 (Box 624b, Folder 20)
    - Nos. 226-250, 1959 (Box 624b, Folder 21)
    - Nos. 251-275, 1959 (Box 624b, Folder 22)
    - Nos. 276-300, 1959 (Box 624b, Folder 23)
    - Nos. 301-325, 1959 (Box 624b, Folder 24)
    - Nos. 326-350, 1959 (Box 624b, Folder 25)
    - Nos. 351-375, 1959 (Box 624b, Folder 26)
    - Nos. 376-400, 1959 (Box 624b, Folder 27)
    - Nos. 401-425, 1959 (Box 624b, Folder 28)
    - Nos. 426-450, 1959 (Box 624b, Folder 29)
    - Nos. 451-475, 1959 (Box 625a, Folder 1)
    - Nos. 476-500, 1959 (Box 625a, Folder 2)
    - Nos. 501-525, 1959 (Box 625a, Folder 3)
    - Nos. 526-550, 1959 (Box 625a, Folder 4)
    - Nos. 551-575, 1959 (Box 625a, Folder 5)
    - Nos. 576-600, 1959 (Box 625a, Folder 6)
    - Nos. 601-625, 1959 (Box 625a, Folder 7)
    - Nos. 626-650, 1959 (Box 625a, Folder 8)
    - Nos. 651-675, 1959 (Box 625a, Folder 9)
    - Nos. 676-700, 1959 (Box 625a, Folder 10)
    - Nos. 701-725, 1959 (Box 625a, Folder 11)
    - Nos. 726-750, 1959 (Box 625a, Folder 12)
    - Nos. 751-775, 1959 (Box 625a, Folder 13)
    - Nos. 776-800, 1959 (Box 625a, Folder 14)
    - Nos. 801-825, 1959 (Box 625a, Folder 15)
    - Nos. 826-850, 1959 (Box 625a, Folder 16)
    - Nos. 851-875, 1959 (Box 625a, Folder 17)
    - Nos. 876-900, 1959 (Box 625a, Folder 18)
    - Nos. 901-925, 1959 (Box 625a, Folder 19)
    - Nos. 926-950, 1959 (Box 625a, Folder 20)
    - Nos. 951-977, 1959 (Box 625a, Folder 21)
    - General, 1959 (Box 625a, Folder 22-23)
  - Sub-Series 523-2. 1959 Grand Lodge Convention. Committee on Grand Lodge Constitution and Laws
    - Resolution Dockets Nos. 1-63, 1959 (Box 625b, Folder 1)
    - Resolution Dockets Nos. 97-137, 1959 (Box 625b, Folder 2)
    - Report of Committee on Grand Lodge Constitution and Laws, 1959 (Box 625b, Folder 3)
      1959 May 8
    - Statutes for the Government of Lodges. Chairman of Laws Committee. Resolution Dockets Nos. 64-96, 1959 (Box 625b, Folder 4)
    - Grand Lodge Copy of Constitution and Laws, 1959 (Box 625b, Folder 5)
    - Grand Lodge Laws, 1959 (Box 625b, Folder 6)
    - Revised Constitution, Statutes for Government of Lodges, and Protective Laws of the Brotherhood, 1959 (Box 625b, Folder 7)
    - Revised Statutes for Government of Lodges, 1959 (Box 625b, Folder 8)
    - Constitution, Statutes for Government of Lodges, and Protective Laws of the Brotherhood, 1955 (Box 625b, Folder 9)
    - Chairman, Laws Committee, 1959 (Box 625b, Folder 10)
    - Report of the Executive Council, American Federation of Labor, 1953 (Box 625b, Folder 11)
      1953 September 21
    - William Green, A Personal Biography (book), by Danish, M.D., 1952 (Box 625b, Folder 12)
    - American Federation of Labor "Legal Information Bulletin", 1926-1932 (Box 625b, Folder 13)
      January 1926-August 1932.
    - Report of Committee on Grand Lodge Constitution and Laws, 1959 (Box 626a, Folder 1-26)
    - Bulletins of American Federation of Labor, 1926-1932 (Box 626a, Folder 27)
  - Sub-Series 523-3. 1959 Grand Lodge Convention. Grand President's Report
    - General, 1957-1959 (Box 626b, Folder 1)
  - Sub-Series 523-4. 1959 Grand Lodge Convention. Appointments
    - Tellers, 1959 (Box 626b, Folder 2)
    - Credentials Committee, 1959 (Box 626b, Folder 3)
    - Delegates; Non-Delegates, 1958-1959 (Box 626b, Folder 4)
    - Convention Committee; Guards; Parliamentarian, 1959 (Box 626b, Folder 5)
    - Committee on Finance, Salaries, Mileage and Per Diem; Grand Chaplain; Committee on Grand Lodge Constitution and Laws; Committee on Appeals; Committee on Petitions and Resolutions; Committee on Credentials; Committee on Unemployment Insurance; Committee on, 1959 (Box 626b, Folder 6)
  - Sub-Series 523-5. 1959 Grand Lodge Convention. Mileage and Per Diem
    - General, 1958-1959 (Box 626b, Folder 7)
  - Sub-Series 523-6. 1959 Grand Lodge Convention. Speakers
    - General, 1959 (Box 626b, Folder 8)
  - Sub-Series 523-7. 1959 Grand Lodge Convention. Hotel Reservations
    - General, 1958-1959 (Box 626b, Folder 9)
  - Sub-Series 523-8. 1959 Grand Lodge Convention. Transportation of Delegates
    - General, 1959 (Box 626b, Folder 10)
  - Sub-Series 523-9. 1959 Grand Lodge Convention. Appeals Committee
    - General, 1959 (Box 626b, Folder 11)
- Series CVIII. AUTOMATION SEVERANCE PAY ALLOWANCE
  - Sub-Series 525-0. Automation Severance Pay Allowance. General
    - General, 1961-1963 (Box 626b, Folder 12)
      1961-March 1963.
    - General, 1957-1960 (Box 626b, Folder 13)
      December 17, 1957-60.
    - United States Department of Labor, Bureau of Labor Statistics, "A Case Study of an Automatic Airline Reservation System", 1958 (Box 626b, Folder 14)
      1958 July
    - General, 1957 (Box 626b, Folder 15)
      October 1957-December 16, 1957.
    - Human Factors in Automation (speech), 1958 (Box 626b, Folder 16)
    - National Industrial Conference Board. "Management's Role in Electronic Data Processing", 1959 (Box 626b, Folder 17)
    - Michigan State University. "Economic and Social Implications of Automation: A Bibliographic Review" (Box 626b, Folder 18)
    - Governor's Conference on Automation, Cooperstown, New York, 1960 (Box 627a, Folder 1)
      June 1-3, 1960.
    - General, 1957 (Box 627a, Folder 2)
      August 16, 1957-September 1957.
    - General, 1957 (Box 627a, Folder 3)
      January 1957-August 15, 1957.
    - General, 1955-1956 (Box 627a, Folder 4)
      October 1955-56.
    - General, 1955 (Box 627a, Folder 5)
      January-September 1955.
- Series CIX. UNITED STATES GOVERNMENT DEPARTMENTS
  - Sub-Series 532-4. United States Government Departments
    - Treasury Department, 1960-1963 (Box 627a, Folder 6)
    - Treasury Department, 1952-1959 (Box 627a, Folder 7)
      June 1952-59.